# **UDAY DEVIKAR**

## Micro-Frontend / Full stack development Guru

Nagpur, India | +918087436966 uday.devikar@gmail.com

## Skills:

### Languages:

- Javascript
- Python
- HTML
- CSS

#### Frameworks:

- ReactJs
- NextJs
- NodeJs
- ExpressJs
- flask
- Storybook
- Storyblok (CMS)

#### **JS Testing frameworks:**

- React testing library
- Jest
- Enzyme

#### **Application logging and monitoring:**

- New Relic
- Splunk

#### **Google Cloud Services:**

- Firebase Real time DB
- Firestore
- DialogFlow
- App Engine
- Compute Engine
- BigQuery

#### Certifications

React Basic - Hackerrank Certificate

ReactJs Advanced - Cutshort Certificate

# **Career Summary:**

Software engineer with **4+ years** of experience in designing and developing frontend web applications. Proficient in modern web technologies including **Javascript**, **ReactJs**, **NextJs**, **NodeJs** and **Micro-Frontend** (**Single-Spa**). Building accessible and progressive web applications observable with web analytics and monitoring.

See **hosted** ReactJs version of my resume <u>here</u>.

## **Experience:**

**Associate Consultant - Infosys** 

October 2022 - Present

## Client: Telstra (MyAccount Rebuild)

- Led the migration efforts of 15 high traffic web pages from legacy application to React.js ensuring a smooth transition while preserving critical functionality and user data.
- Developed react components with focus on accessibility ensuring all interactive elements comply with WCAG (Web Content Accessibility Guidelines) standards.
- Collaborated closely with cross functional teams, including backend developers, QA team and project managers. Facilitated effective communication to ensure seamless integration process.

Software Engineer - MediaAgility

August 2020 - October 2022

Client: WNS ( OPUS Chrome Extension )

- Single handedly designed and developed highly scalable and maintainable chrome extension which reduced business teams manual intervention by 90%
- Strong alignment with backend team to collaborate and design a PostgreSQL database to align in with chrome extension indexed db.
- Actively took part in project from Requirement Analysis, SOW Estimation to project delivery
- Tools Used:- JavaScript, MySql, Firebase Real Time DB, Github,

## Client: Springboard

- Built highly reusable and maintainable ui component in Gatsby and React Js
- worked on website performance campaign which increased the website lighthouse score from 60s to 80s
- Worked on Refactoring codebases from AngularJs to React Js
- Tools Used:- React Js, Gatsby, Storybook, Storyblok, Bitbucket, Confluence

## **Client: Caresyntax**

**Description:** Designed and developed a sophisticated web application utilizing ReactJs for caresyntax client facilitating a seamless video upload to google cloud storage with google resumable upload functionality, leveraged advanced web technologies including service workers and Indexed DB for offline capability and data storage

## **Key contributions:**

- **Architect** and **developed** react based application from scratch, catering a specific requirement for care syntax client for **video upload**, **management** and **analytics**.
- Integrated google **cloud storage** with the application, utilizing google **resumable upload** functionality for uploading large **video files** up to **1 GB**
- Implemented service workers and Indexed DB to implement offline functionality.
- Incorporated keycloak authentication and authorization into react application, ensuing robot security measures to protect sensitive users data features
- Designed and developed a dashboard pages using ChartJs library to showcase key performance Index (KPIs) of uploaded video, providing valuable insights for users to track and analyze video performance
- Integrated MediaElement.js library to seamlessly enable robust video playback capability
- added **contextual markers** functionality to include descriptive **tooltip**, providing users contextual information about key moments into video.

#### Client: Whatfix chatbot POC

**Description:** Developed a customized **chatbot** application tailored for the sales team, enabling seamless management of upcoming meetings and opportunities. The chatbot provided a user-friendly interface for sales representatives to interactively **schedule**, **update**, and **retrieve** information about their meetings and associated opportunities.

#### **Key contributions:**

- Engineered chatbot solution using **DialogFlow**, React Redux and **NodeJs** Specifically designed to cater the needs of the sales team.
- Integrated Google login and salesforce login feature, allowing users to authenticate using their accounts securely.
- Created an api integrating a google calendar api to get updates of upcoming meetings.
- Orchestrated a **backend logic** and API endpoints using NodeJs facilitating seamless communication between frontend google calendar api

#### **Education:**

#### Government College of Engineering, Jalgaon

Bachelor of technology (B.Tech), Electrical Engineering, 2015 - 2019

## Nirala Junior College, Nagpur

Higher Secondary, General Science, 2014 - 2015

#### **Personal Details:**

**D. O. B.:** Uday Devikar 12 Dec 1997 **Mobile No:** +91 8087436966

Email Id: uday.devikar@gmail.com

Linkedin: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/uday-devikar-101867130/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/uday-devikar-101867130/</a>

Github: <a href="https://github.com/UdayDevikar">https://github.com/UdayDevikar</a>